I am interested in education data and have previously done homeworks for this class using Maryland education data. I went to Maryland over spring break and took the Metro into D.C., so naturally I wondered if students use it often. The question that this map answers is “Is the Baltimore Metro an effective mode of transportation for students?”. I used datasets of Baltimore County (BCPSS) K-12 school locations and of Baltimore Metro stops to do this analysis. I created a 0.5 mile buffer around the Metro stops to classify each circle as “walkable”. The walk from the Metro stop would ideally be short, especially for children. I then created an intersection layer of the schools within the 0.5 mile radius, which are the schools that the Metro would likely serve the most. This map tells us that most Baltimore schools are not in the vicinity of a Metro stop. If the buffer radius was extended to 1 mile, the community would seem more walkable.
